Ilias Olakunle Shittu-Gbeko

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

With more than three years of dedicated experience in efficiently gathering, synthesising, and presenting information, I excel at applying analytical and critical problem-solving skills to derive valuable insights from data. Experienced in creating compelling stories and insightful reports that offer conclusions to problem statements in research spheres. I have a proven track record of delivering tasks with highly organised and detailed-oriented information in various analytical domains such as engineering, business, and technology.

CORE SKILLS/COMPETENCIES

Data Entry and Management

Microsoft Excel, Google sheets, Azure Data Studio

Stats & Experimentation

Hypothesis Testing, Predictive Modelling, Time Series Analysis and Regression Analysis

Other Technical Skills

Office Productivity Tools: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint.

Google Office Package: Google Docs, Sheets and Slides

Notion

Canva

Sway and OneNote

Writing and Research Tools

Grammarly, scispace, zotero, mendeleey cite, Connected papers, scholarcy, elicit, QuillBot, Wordtune, scite, semantic scholars, research rabbit, consensus, Notion, Adjust

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Junior Technical Writer

Statcomm Consult and Technology

04/2024 - present Ibadan, Nigeria

- · designed and prepared a proposal for an agricultural empowerment project for Nigerian youth, providing land access, training, and ongoing support to establish sustainable agribusiness ventures.
- conducted a comprehensive analysis of On The Beach Group PLC, covering strategic, financial, and ESG perspectives for investment decision-making.
- · demonstrated practical IT skills by creating organised folders, gathering information, compiling Word documents, and efficiently emailing professors and stakeholders.

Technical Writer 01/2022 - 03/2024 Tailan Consults & Lagos, Nigeria

- · Analyzed income inequality trends using LIS dataset . Applied sophisticated quantitative models, addressing redistribution paradox. Produced a clear info graph, report and research article based on the analysis.
- Led creation of BM134 report, applying advanced frameworks for strategic analysis of Microsoft UK. Integrated theory with practical insights for optimal understanding
- Performed a comprehensive international marketing assessment of Nestle Plc's entry strategies, segmentation, and overall effectiveness in Nigeria and Malaysia.

EDUCATION

Professional Diploma in Data Analytics

Baze University, Abuja &

02/2024 - present Abuja, Nigeria

B.Eng (First Class Honours) in Materials and Metallurgical Engineering

Federal University of Technology, Minna

2017 - 2023Minna, Nigeria

VOLUNTEERING

ATC Africa Cyber Smart Volunteer 09/2023 - present

Nigeria

Joined forces with other amazing volunteers in promoting internet safety and digital literacy in Minna City. Its importance lies in creating a safer online environment while empowering individuals with the knowledge and skills to navigate the digital world securely

Insight_IQ HDSC Fall 2023

Project Lead

- Coordinated and led the team to provide and end to end data science project on Global Energy Transition Analysis a
- Developed a 92% Energy Forecasting model for predicting 20 countries energy goals for 2020-2030

Data Scientist Network (Futminna Campus)

AI/ML Education Volunteer

Conducted an AI invasion program to bring AI education close to a much wider audience. The largest community of data science and artificial intelligence Data Scientist Network sponsored this event

Go Skills Excel Community \mathscr{D}

Community Educator

- Facilitated interactive Excel training sessions, developed educational content, and provided personalized guidance to learners.
- Actively participated in community forums, offering expert insights on Excel-related topics.
 Contributed to fostering a supportive and collaborative learning environment.

Academic Study Circle Initiative

Minna, Nigeria

STEM Tutor

Mentoring of students at the School of Engineering, Futminna on python programming language and other AI tools and emerging technologies.

AWARDS

Top ML Contributor

MLSA Nigeria

Awarded for my immense contribution to cutting edge open source research project in Machine Learning organized Microsoft Learn Student Community in Nigeria

Winner, Cyber Smart 2023 Competition

ATC Africa

Achieved 1st place in Cybersecurity Challenge, showcasing strong skills in data analysis and problem-solving

Top rated Competitor

Go Skills Excel Community

Achieved a track record of 28 challenges in less than a month in the excel challenge tournament

Best Student in the department

Vice Chancellor's Award of Academic Excellence